all right welcome to
our saturday round table i feel like i
want to invite people to come on but no
one's watching so they're going to watch
the beginnings i'm going to wait till
there's a viewer and then be like if you
want to join
follow the stream yard link we have a
stream yard link every week
in facebook so that you can join and
give us your update on what your project
is
and what you could use help with because
that's what we're here to do is help
each other with our projects and create
a better
omniwin world so this is where we
discuss tell you what our project is
what we've been up to and what we could
use help with
atrial do you want to start uh sure
so my project uh there's sort of two
they're
two sides of the same thing there's
wikilection which i've been talking
about for a while
and then the new version which is sort
of the parent to everything which is
conferrati
um that is going well the prototype for
for wiki election um we've been building
that
and i believe i'm supposed to be getting
a new version
hopefully sometime soon um we've been i
think squirreling a bit
on one of the features that was supposed
to be fairly simple because it was a
prototype
but i think uh our two coders may have
used that term again scrolled a bit and
uh
gotten sort of a deep dive in that
feature which is fine it sounds like a
bunch of other projects
we'll be able to use it um i actually
spoke to
a person from an accelerator in florida
yet yesterday who did like if they have
an accelerator for social enterprises
um and that includes like i guess
for-profit businesses that have some
sort of like you know they pay x percent
towards something
or just straight-up nonprofits um
and so that sounds interesting so i'll
be sending an application for that
because
apparently the timeline for that
wouldn't
conflict with my day job which is nice
um so we'll be doing that
possibly that'll be good and that is
where the the project is at
all right and i am jubilee and my
projects are solution raising and my new
project which is
better modern learning magic working
title so the acronym is mlm
and um solution raising we held it on
war this
week and i don't wouldn't say we failed
to come up with something but we got off
topic a lot it was more about
interpersonal war like you know
masks not masks and that kind of thing
rather than war
in general and then this next week we're
going to do it on humor
on comedy and humor i have no idea
because i'm like does that need to be
fixed i don't know but eric suggested it
so we're gonna do it on that um
the mlm i've been in talking to several
people it might be raymond and carrie
and i who started
it might be this other person who who i
talk to if we want to do the six week
course together
i uh one thing i could use help with
this week although it's only you of
course
is um how last week went like how
after we talked about yeah how last week
went right did you feel empowered after
talking about your issue in order to
take any action that was
what you wouldn't have taken anyway or
you know like what was the actual impact
and i'm looking to think about like um
i'm going to be starting the six week
course that will be the product for the
mlm
and look and who who to start it with do
i want to start it with with life
coaching people
who generally have a high paid life
coach that they would work with
or because i have a lot of people in
that community or do i want to do game b
people or random people like who is it
that um
who is it i kind of want to do all three
let's see
participate in all of them and see where
they go but i don't even i barely have
the spoons to add one thing to my plate
let alone
all of them well i'm also you know the
coordinator for the teacher for my kid
and doing all of all of that as well so
that is a bit of my update now we can
have an open conversation and bentley's
not joining us today he's moving he's
taking the day
just to be clear he's uh he wasn't a
no-show he's just not
not here as i don't think anyone thinks
bentley's a no-show i don't think anyone
sees his personality as as flaky in any
way as maybe mine is but i also show up
every week so i just did a video this
morning on overest
underestimators and how much i'm
definitely an underestimator but we hire
the overestimators
and um yeah i'm going to be looking at
trying to correct
just a little bit of that language not
because i want to be an overestimator
but i don't want to come off as an
underestimator if that makes any sense
even though i want the underestimator to
inform my personality because i think
that underestimators show up better in
this world
and yeah in the long term yeah sorry but
to your point like if you have
to choose between two people and someone
is like i'm not sure and someone's like
i'm amazing
yeah that's literally what the video was
it's like would you hire boss who's an
over estimator or ruby who's an
underestimator with the
assumption they're at the exact same
skill level you're always going to hire
bob the overestimator
and ruby's always going to show up
better if they're the same skill level
right and of course being an
underestimator makes you show up with
higher skill and being an underestimator
makes you
or wrestling or stories like i'm already
good i need to do anything
so it's like they start the same and
actually diverge
you're always going to hire bob and yet
you should have always hired ruby is
basically the outcome yeah it's very
adjustable i think it's uh
you know kind of like an and x on a
graph for like
although it's a weirdly shaped one
because they overlapped pretty quickly
where it's like you hire bob's
overestimator you know you're like
you're looking good you're looking at it
you probably give him the benefit of the
doubt for the first week or two and then
you're like
i don't think bob is very good if you
actually you know go through training
and see bob do work you're like
bob doesn't know how to do this i just
asked the most basic question and he
didn't know what that word meant
that's a standard thing everyone who
knows this knows right so you're someone
who's actually hired people so let's say
you hire bob
and um he's he sucks and you fire bob
two weeks later and now you're going to
hire the next person
you're still going to hire an
overestimator right you're still going
to hire that person now you're going to
look for something
better the interview process is to avoid
that
right it's it's not about
underestimators it's do you actually
know what you say you know
hey carrie hello
um one example of that was i i was
working at a software company
and we had just hire i remember if we
hired him
no he was just doing an interview and
this guy was a developer it
resumed out the like out the door it was
awesome our
development manager was like there's no
way this guy is going to want to work
here he's way too much experience
blah blah blah so he you know just
went through the uh the process anyway
had the guy do the
the the development interview
which there was like a really small
coding challenge like you know just go
here and
encode this and uh the guy asked our
development manager like well how do i
do that
he's like well you start off by starting
a class he's like so how do i do that
and that's when our developer realized
like oh this guy can't do
anything his resume says he can do like
it's
all a lot every single word and then he
asked a couple more questions and yeah
and found out it was all complete bs and
so
the job of the interview is to make sure
that you're not just relying on what
the resume says the person can do you
know you actually phone
the references hopefully and you know
figure out
how good the person was you ask them
questions to see do they actually know
what they say they're gonna know
which generally means that it can't just
be you know an hr person
doing it because i've been on the other
end of that where it's just somebody who
doesn't know the
thing at all and that makes the company
look bad kind of the opposite where the
company seems like maybe the company's
in
over estimator fair enough cara do you
want to
tell us your project and where you are
with it and what's going on
oh jeez i don't know where to start
really um
well as you know like my life went to
in a big way
so as i said it went downhill
downhill pretty fast kind of hit rock
bottom and
it made me question everything about me
and what i'm gonna do and i was like oh
i was like well what you know i know me
plans of what
where they'd like to go but obviously i
can't do any of them
because of circumstances and stuff so i
thought well what do i love
right and there's one thing that you
said to me um jubilee
a while back saying um you know you said
you
you're really funny which but you never
really saw it myself i
i thought well what what do i love doing
i said well i love crocheting
nice i love making people laugh and
i i want a community so anyway because
i'd kind of
started crocheting and decided to call
me self bad nana beans right for
i thought well okay i'll i'll make a go
of bad nana beans and then
i thought i oh there's no money
coming in after so like a certain dick's
got major redundance and that and i'm
like oh what am i gonna do
so i'm gonna have to ask people for
money to keep me going and then
my friends are starting a bookkeeping
business and she's really good
like whereas i'm all over the place i've
sort of big ideas big pictures they
the details and like she's all
details and stuff so
starting to collaborate with them we're
like well she's got no clout hardly any
clients she
left and she's like at that crossroads
point as well so
anyway um i got a bit of redundancy and
um i asked my mum if she'd give me money
for the year because she did offer to
pay some of my mortgage off because i've
only got a year or two
three left and i thought well if you
leave
if you do that for me i'm still going to
be up creek without a battle
because i've still got no money because
nobody wants to give me a job because
i've been applying for jobs all over the
place right
so anyway so bad nana beans right i
thought i'll crochet stuff for people
and then i took a deep dive into the
crochet world
and how to make money through crochet
and everyone was going
just like okay and then he said you've
got to have seven different streams of
income and i thought i
okay so i kind of got two maybe so far
and i'm okay till december 21
but after that i was like right okay so
so so
there's that and with me mate leon and
then the idea of the pirates of the
crafty being
came came to light because there's a lot
of people out there who make
crafts do crafts but they don't really
fit in
to these whales that are out there and
there's loads of people who make one-off
stuff
never to be made again and i've had a
lot of so i took a deep dive into etsy
and all the marketplaces
and i was like ugh and i listened to
loads of people who
kind of been thrown off the site and
there was one particular instance where
there was a woman and she'd been on
there for seven years making money with
her jewelry
and she got ill and obviously she'd
revolted all her customers and
and stuff back and she'd moved and she
said the glue and the heat
of the eric you know and earlier fell to
pieces so she ended up having to do that
and she got ill
and they wouldn't give her a shot back
after seven years of plowing all that
effort
into sort of like you know generating
okay stuff for yourself but also
when people come to eures they're shown
other people's stuff as well
and i thought right okay so i'd dive
into that
and i thought right i'd like something
like that but i don't
i don't want to be like them you know
what i mean i don't want to be so
i realize with bad nana beans like i
think i want to do it as a collective
um and i want to build a marketplace but
i want
i want people to come for the community
first
and then for the marketplace you know i
mean
and um so that's the and the pilots of
the crafty being right i know
i was off so like years of doing
different stuff and fingers in lots of
pies i realized a load
i know a load of people from all
different backgrounds and everybody's
kind of siloed off into the
this is photographers this is for
filmmakers this is for that
that's for that so as i said i thought
the pirates of the crafty bean could be
kind of like a social
social club sort of thing you know and
um
jubilee which when you sent me that um
barbara share video
about the idea parties and stuff like
that so i think underneath
the banner of the pirates of the crafty
being um i'd like to host like idea
parties
and stuff like that as well so as i said
this
and i came up with it and i said i
looked into sales and marketing and all
the digital marketing
and i thought oh as i said i felt dirty
it felt kind of slimy
and everybody and i know everybody's
going towards ai
and stuff like that and automated
messages and and
to be honest right because i've been
quite depressed over the past
few weeks all you'll ever get because
because i'm nosy you're gonna sign up
for a lot of things
all you get is all these ai messages
going
hi would you like to buy my shirt would
you like to buy my shirt
oh we cared about you we haven't seen
you for a while would you like to buy my
shirt
and i thought you have got a
idea how
your automated message which everybody
knows is automated
and you know this is like this fake sort
of care
and i remember one guy sort of like sent
me an email like stolen the virtues of
ai
and automated messages and all it said
was hi
first name
and i just thought there's got to be a
better way
of of sales and marketing i'm going to
have to have a look at all the
traditional stuff
and i think i need a mentor in
traditional sales and marketing and
things
because i know that i know there's
something in there that can maybe do
better
um or maybe change it so it's not a
shitty you know i mean
and so so yeah so look i'm i'm spending
the
now till december kind of making stuff
right and then kind of taking that time
to actually think about stuff and think
about what i want
and as you know i'm not very good at
planning and schedule and like that
so i'm gonna have to learn that as well
so i'm gonna have to learn everything so
i feel like oh i've just sort of like
started again
and but yeah so someone said i was
crocheting
people into existence i said oh okay
then maybe i should start taking
photographs and crochet
have a crochet jubilee i think i'll eat
a crochet jubilee a crochet angel and
crochet bentley
[Laughter]
well i see i thought you're using my
name in the other sense i was gonna i
was gonna say actually i thought this
week because
i don't have anything you can make for
me but then i wear this hat all
winter but it's got a whole lot in it
and it's
it's getting it's getting bad i want a
black one that's basically the same
okay do you want you want the things
but yeah you said you could only crochet
for people you know and i was like oh i
could use you know something like that
with maybe just a little bit of chicken
things the flaps
[Laughter]
mentally i can't find my other one i get
cold
right so you want to tell you right
because hats was obvious because people
have started asking did you beat these i
said well i've never
never crocheted them before because i've
never had anybody because i don't wear
that
and so um i'm having to set up a
questionnaire and a survey to send out
to people so they can fill in because
like
there's lots of stuff like because i'm
not interested in any of it it's really
odd
to think i'll just crochet this you know
i mean so
i've done pots for home decor which
quite everyone's kind of been drooling
about
the proper proper versions of them and
that um but yeah so beanies any
particular you want black
my mom actually got this for me over a
decade ago it was from a place here
called 10 villages which is like from
all over the world they
theoretically use fair trade and then
they they sell it
so i think it's from some one of the
south american countries i actually
don't know
little tassel on the top that part i
probably don't need but the tassel will
be
on the bottom i do it's part i like it
over my ears and
even though it's weird because it it
hurts my single side of deafness but i
i like it and it's what i'm using we
literally wear it
from about october to april
may okay i'll dig out some patterns and
i'll send you the patterns and then you
can tell me which ones you like
also jubilee i met somebody who i hadn't
seen for about 20 odd years
right and um basically
we're on the same kind of level right
he's got autism
right with with other stuff as well and
i was going to introduce him but i
thought he's driving me insane
right and he and you know what i love it
right i really like him and he's a kind
person and he showed me this project
thing that he had for the co-operative
club and i thought
jubilee and then i thought no i'd she'll
make mince meat out of them
[Laughter]
i don't like mix people don't know
i didn't know whether to introduce you
because like i'm sitting there like he's
the kindest person in the world
and i'm just sitting there and i'm
telling and he's like
[Laughter]
you know what i mean and then i spoke to
me at it and he said look i'm better if
i'm just delivering a video
i said yes steve so i'm hopefully speak
to him like that but he's a bit
entrenched
with this thing which was kind of like
part of this network i was on years ago
it was called the academy
and the owner apparently well story
about this academy website right it was
about networking and business and this
and that and the other and how
networking and and the leader of that
site the owner of that site was going
extolling the virtues of networking and
i just thought he was a bit of a wanker
to be honest right
so i basically out networked him on his
own website
you know i mean so
but and he set up this kind of like
black story academy
with you know and um you have to pay
about two grand to join
and stuff like that as well and and it's
and it's kind of part of this
this person that which i won't name just
in case again done for slander or
whatever
anyway steve was part of this black star
academy and i remembered him paying for
me to go to the house of lords dinner
one time right so that's that's that's
how kind he was but he used to get
slaughtered because i didn't know back
then he had autism you know what i mean
and other stuff going on
but he the way he came across and that
used to sort of like rub everybody up
the wrong way
and at that time nobody really kind of
probably realized he just thought he was
being a bit
of a good you know to be honest and
anyway um
yeah so he's had all this but you know
the sad thing
is he's been entrenched in this thing
and i can see good bits in this thing
but it just
feels a bit like a cult right and i'm
just like steve but
but what i'm what i've realized today i
think
people have taken advantage of them
right
i think they've taken advantage of it is
it his company did he come up with the
idea or is it somebody
no no no no it's somebody else's right
it sounds an awful lot like an mlm and
not a qualifier well this is
a thousand dollars to join it and yeah
no this was just sort of like a
networking
thing and and stuff like that way back
when yeah
so um like thinking back like after me
last
sort of like chat with him and what he's
been telling me over the past 15 years
because he says i've got a lot of
knowledge
and him and then he started speaking
about the holochain and i thought
raymond do i introduce him to raymond
and i thought
oh my god that would be like clash of
the titans and stuff
well yeah well raymond used to tell me
that you know he used to get thrown out
of places
for just asking questions too many
questions
and i thought oh you know what i mean
and then and then steve goes to me
you know you're one of the very few
people who you know i mentioned the
holochain to and you know what it is
but i think and i'm feeling quite sad
now because as i said because while i
was chatting to him because he
he's great at doing a video but in live
chats
he's not he goes off all over on
tangents and i know
i go off on tangents all over the place
but he's well kind of and we've got the
same
kind of profile what this thing is
because he give me this
thing to do and he was like you're just
a mirror you're just a mirror
right okay so but i think i think what's
happened is i think
people have taken advantage of them over
the past
15 years you know what i mean like and i
just don't know how to
kind of like there's nothing i can do to
fix that
but you know i think most of his
reactions are
part of that which is why he's kind of
you know what i mean but as i said i
wanted to introduce him to you
because i know he's all about the co-op
and stuff you know i'm down with it
i'm always down right my issue is yes
sometimes i can get a little
because it's what i want people to do
for me with my project like i get so
annoyed it's the wrong word but it's
like okay either i get i'm saying i have
a world saving project and i can't
necessarily
explain it although i think i'm doing a
pretty good job of making it so i think
i'm okay
but like either it's true
right i actually do know how to save the
world in which case
listen for a second right like
try to understand it because i can't
explain it
or i don't right if i'm delusional
break it for me because it's gonna break
me and my like my my family my life
everything and if it's
is then listen and it's like instead
everyone kind of has this gray area of
like
we'll just let her do her thing and it's
like no
either break it or don't like it's like
they're it's
it's not a kindness and so for me i try
i
forget that other people maybe don't
want that and so i try to break their
thing for them and it's like
oh you don't want this broken okay i'm
sorry i'm sorry that's not
and so now and i don't want it like the
people who like i just i met someone who
is doing a similar thing on mlm and
cooperative and omni-win
and he is more competent than i am he's
more charismatic he's more of a business
person he's actually been successful in
actual mlms
and i'm like oh you might succeed at
this thing you're making but the thing
you're making is flawed
but you might succeed at it but other
people aren't necessarily going to
succeed at it
and there's that level of like for him i
don't feel like i need to break it
because he might make it work right
and so but someone else when i'm if like
someone else brought that to me and i'd
be like
not going to work because one you don't
have the experience you didn't
you weren't successful in an mlm like
there's very different qualities
but yeah that that part of what i'm
dealing with in the world is i do want a
like weirdo revolution like i'm on an
authentic autistic
like and so then i come up against
people who rub me the wrong way or who
personalities are in conflict and i'm
like
but not you and i'm like right that's my
are you interrupting people are you
going on tangents that's so annoying
so this so so like i also said i was
debating whether to introduce
you to each other because i think that
you know
um but as i said i realized
talking to him i realized the value
of having a a small
commute like i really want a community
that actually
gives a about the people in the
community and it's a two-way street
i don't want white street because i
realize having like cause he was going
on about he's got 13 000 in his network
and
apparently he sent this thing out to he
sent me an invite to this thing called
the lunch club
where you put in your details and have
random chats with whoever
and he said i was one of the very few
people
out of the 13 000 people who actually
got in touch with them
now to me that that displays right
yes you can have a big network of people
but if they don't give a about you
there's no way anything what you do
is is gonna have any impact in that
whereas smaller communities
and people who actually do give a
about you and want you to succeed
as you wanna help them succeed because
as i said i've sat and
really thought about myself and what is
it what is it that i keep doing
and i and even like i've been told right
you should focus on yourself focus on
yourself
but that doesn't make me feel good right
um
i feel better when i could just help and
help and help
but what i realized i open up and help
and yet the help is not coming back to
me
you know what i mean and therefore you
know i get bogged down with stuff
but even though i try and say right i'm
not helping anybody i just can't
help it
you know what i mean it's not it's not
even gaa
yeah to sort of like say no you know i
mean and i've always put orders first
like i remember when i used to after
when i was doing courses and i was doing
exams and i never used to hear from
people
at all on the day before the
exam someone would phone me about a
disaster in their life right
so and i'm like well i can't
just say like
no sorry call me back in three months
time you really can
you really can by the way well i don't
know i have to say i mean now that
this is part of me feeling like i'm here
to save the world and i have this idea
in me i've literally cut out all of the
drama for my life i'm like i'm sorry i
can't deal with you and your
relationship
i have to deal with the world and
if i knew that they like there's people
i'm like listen i'm here for you
call me if you need me but like i should
be fourth or fifth down the list right
like
the first ones aren't like yes come to
me but everyone has drama everyone lives
paycheck to paycheck everyone has
constant drama
because they don't have big world
savings to deal with
because their heads in the stand for all
of that stuff and it's like either we
concentrate on the mundane that
honestly anyone can deal with
so go find someone else to deal with it
i'm here to save the world
and that sounds selfish and it feels
selfish in the moment because i'm like
no i really do want to be here for my
friends and family
and i want but then i don't have the
energy to do the other stuff and
anyone can be here for your breakup that
is gonna you're gonna get back together
in a week anyway
i not everyone can change the world and
so
it's like where is your focus where is
your energy
better used and then if you're also like
listen i'm helping everyone and no one's
helping me
there's that
i know you're not doing it for a tit for
tat because that's not your personality
when it starts to feel like that it's
like don't do anything you wouldn't do
without any reciprocity right like if
you and that's part of it is i
also realized that i don't call people
when i'm hurting because that's not my
personality especially the people who
call me when they're hurting
and expect me to be their emotional
support i
aren't safe spaces and i can't call them
and events because they're
judgmental as and so it's like wait
a minute this isn't
no i'm going to give my spoons of
emotional energy to anyone else because
you have other friends you have other
people go to them
go to the ones that you're actually
going to listen to anyway because they
also
don't necessarily listen to my advice
and so it's like drains all of my energy
i feel bad because i'm
i'm an empath and i'm like no you deal
with your own you're on your own
roller coaster
everyone is responsible for their own
and i'm more concentrating on like the
meta
right how do we get everyone help when
they're in a relationship problem how do
we get everyone help when they're in a
mental health crisis
so i can't deal with your mental health
crisis you know what i mean like
yours i'm deal i would be happy to deal
with because i know
but seriously i did get to the very end
and i was just like
i just can't i thought why why am i here
what
why what's the point you know i mean and
then
but going back to the fun bit what you
said that'll make people laugh and that
so i had an idea for the pirates of the
crafty being
is to do just to do these little
vignettes like films this short
short clips of something um
called second opens pills of wisdom from
the pirates
so if you think of um one-liners
that make you laugh you know what i mean
because i'm gonna do them i'm speaking
to me filmmaker friends on
um monday there's something on fire
is that buzzing or is that just me we've
got something in the mirrors
right yeah so i'm speaking to my friend
my filmmaker friend on monday
so i'm going to see if she'll shoot them
so the idea is to get different
people who are kind of because i i said
to john
one of the guys who does embroidery i
said look these little vignettes and
that and he just
you know where you're just sitting there
doing what you're doing and then just
look up and deliver one line
and i was talking to him and i said you
know do these videos you have one line
that's called
pills of wisdom and that and he just
looked and he said what like this and he
went
did you enjoy the play mrs lincoln
and i never got the reference at the
time because i didn't know what he was
talking about
and stuff like that so um hopefully bad
nana beans might get uh
might get a chat show
with all kinds of there's a um raymond
was using it and actually who else i
think it was eric who
um there's they're nearly identical i
like the the one that raymond used
better and i don't know what the names
are so i can get you the names
but they're basically just a room that
you go in you have a little avatar and
when you walk up close to people you it
go it goes into the video and gets
clearer audio and then when you walk
away from people
um it's like being a physical person
right that would happen if we were in a
room of people except when i walk
i don't have to hear all the background
noise of all the other conversations so
this works better for me
but doing something like that with
crafting
it's free for up to 10 people i think
the one eric has is free for up to 20
people
and having that is the craft session
where people can get together in groups
of two or you can go wander over here
and wander over there and do that you
know it might be something that's free
that
can start that and having craft hour
or craft two hours on the um the one um
every week right and seeing can you
build it up and build that community and
doing something because it's free so it
doesn't need the other thing when you
were talking about marketing and how it
leaves that bad taste and we were
talking just before you came on the
overestimation
uh video i just put out and just that
that most people are either over
underestimators and i think marketing
is broken at the overestimation level
right like you just like with people
everyone's going to overestimate their
product it's what you have to do you're
not going to be able to do it without it
but then we all know that everything in
marketing is overestimation
so nobody trusts it and so it's about
recalibrating that trust and like adrian
was saying it's not really
about is he gonna hire the next over
underestimator it's like what is their
actual skill set from the resume
um and give the truth right what is
their actual skill level
and that is what we need to do with
marketing right it's like what does this
actually do
not what do you promise it does and how
does it compare to everything else in
the marketplace
that's not something one person can fix
it's something we have to fix together
right like it's marketing's so broken
that you can't really game be it without
creating game b
and yet the first thing that comes up
that does that that truly is a yelp for
the people
if we have the threshold of people who
know about it i think it'll be it'll be
well one of the reasons why i wanted to
set up a bad nana beans as a collective
right
as i said i've got a friend in australia
who also does crochet
and i thought it'd be great like because
because of the postage and shipping
and someone from the uk and i'm speaking
to my friend
jill and think she's in santa monica and
she's been making stuff on etsy
and stuff and she said i can't even send
stuff to the uk it won't it won't allow
anyone from the uk to buy stuff so i
thought well with the crochet
side of it i could get me and vicky like
so she's in australia someone buys from
australia
she's got the pattern and the stuff to
make it with you know i mean
um
one-liner thing is so interesting i've
been discussing with few friends about
so many one-liners or phrases and
numerous different cultures in india
that could be revived in interesting
ways
that'd be cool too is having especially
i think we talked about um
i don't know if it resonated with you
but like having people who
are maybe refugees or immigrants who
are teaching you their craft right and
having that conversation and hearing
well well i've spoken i've spoken to um
like because every
for the past couple of months um there's
monty
right uh her descendants are from india
and she got the
she bought the police box on these walk
and she does these pop-up shops and that
so every tuesday
and thursday i've been going up there
because what happens is they get
the refugee community kitchen um
they get food from the supermarket
that's been out a day
so they get that so the stuff that they
can't use
um so so they touch them a couple of
them
take about a buck a pop-up shop and we
give out free food
um you know what i mean and i was
discussing this idea
of of with joe who's sort of like a
trained therapist and stuff and have
been discussing to her about you know
the idea for arts and crafts and
things like that and i would like to
actually
and she said she mentioned the refugees
and their crafts and stuff you know what
i mean so this is why
um i know i can't get an actual physical
location
that we could actually get together just
yet um
but part of the pirates of the crafty
being and that
hopefully you create enough revenue to
actually maybe get a start of somewhere
we could have static
like we can go to other places once the
restrictions are lifted
but yeah we need a place we can actually
sit and plan
and then people can actually drop in and
and do things
yeah even i mean right now is the
perfect time to start it online because
yeah
the world and so using one of those
other ones the one that i i like that i
was on with raymond
you can upload a picture so you could
have a pirate ship and then people could
walk along the pirate ship and you know
what i mean like
we'll be crafting in the gallows or i
don't know what parts of ships are
called
so gallows is i don't i don't think
whatever the gallery
is but finding those those ways of
bringing it online
and maybe doing just one that's local
saying that we're going to be
at this pub once the restrictions are
locked down but start building that
community
start fight you know inviting the people
who are local who are the refugees to
start having those conversations and
seeing
is it developing um as that that
community would they be open to being
interviewed on a camera right like what
what are those those things but you know
i wanted to check in with you
on um yeah like i said before before
carrick came on what
how last week was for you and whether
you found anything different over the
last week having done the peer
coaching whatever we're calling it um
i mean it was a bit different i think i
had been sort of in the mindset of
changing things anyway
um so
i haven't dealt with the things that we
talked about specifically but like
that's
it has sort of you know put a bug in my
ear on like that i probably should start
paying attention to that
do you think it would be um use like if
you were in a six-week course where you
kept showing up week after week so that
each week you have that little bit of
like oh yeah i did or didn't do it right
and so
having that that's definitely one of the
things that i've noticed just throughout
my life that like makes me do something
is if i say i'm gonna do it especially
like if it's you know
in front of other people like the best
my best record for actually like
regularly going to the gym was when i
had a gym partner right and it was like
it was actually a gym in my building so
it was a friend of mine who afterwards
like
because it was just from there straight
to work he had to use my shower and
stuff
it forced me to go to the gym because it
was like if i didn't go he
couldn't go to the gym so yeah no i
found for me
i mean i naturally because i never
forced anything but naturally seemed to
want i talked to to my roommate
about getting a um a a cleaner because
it's like if we can't keep the house
clean then let's
figure out how to how to do that it'll
take the end so just having that
conversation and looking into it
is more than i've done over the last few
weeks right so like that natural
progression
we just did a bit of peer coaching where
what kind of like the idea cafe
idea that's idea party
i was like i didn't get those mine um
idea party with uh where we brought
and i just asked us all to bring
something in our lives how it is
how we would like it to be and what's
stopping us and so mine was that my
house is a mess and april's was his add
right and keeping things um on track and
then bentley's not here so i'm not sure
his
but um yeah and seeing where where that
because that's what the project for the
mlm
is is a six week course and that's not
even paid it's a free six week course
show up and peer coach each other
right and so it's funny because i talked
to someone yesterday who is a life coach
and he was like well i wouldn't want to
do that because i would want
like he doesn't he's above those people
right like it's like well i'd be the one
coaching them i'm like no you wouldn't
because that's not the the point isn't
there's a coach right so if you're doing
that you're actually not doing what
you're supposed to be doing
but i'm like honestly if anyway because
i also have life coaching i have a few
people i know with life coaching i'm
like what if we got a bunch of life
coaches together to peer coach each
other
that would be interesting um because
it's like right you don't get to be the
expert this is the whole point is it's
like what in you says is the next step
and then you're a little bit more
empowered a reality show that could get
very entertaining
yes yes it is true and yeah how to
how to move forward with that and
creating the um
the community because i think the i'm
focused on broadcast i still
am i'm still like how do i grow my
youtube channel how do i get more
followers how do i do that because it
feels like that's what
should happen right like i should have
that so i can get but i'm like oh that
actually isn't
how this is going to go it's going to be
very interconnected where it's like oh i
only have to find 10 people
i don't need to find 10 000. and we just
have to create something for us
and then keep moving out without getting
too big right without getting the um
that grandiose well wait like this is
the utopian how do we move towards the
utopian we don't we just
how do we invite the hundred and the
thousand and the ten thousand and
growing out in that way
that works for people and part of it is
dealing with a six-week course of
is it working right if no one's getting
anything out of it but i think part of
it is people have this vision
like if you thought that coming to you
last week's would then cure your adhd
right it's clearly not living up to that
but if the next week you've just done
that little bit of extra like you said
it was it was
you were already thinking about it
that's the whole point you were already
thinking about you already are your own
coach you don't need an outside coach
it's just that little bit of like and
then someone says something that
resonates with you or someone says
something that triggers you
either way it's helpful right you should
make medications
i think you and i are the kind of people
that wouldn't do well with having a life
coach
like i'm not really not that kind of
person peer is fine
but oh hey that's coach like not my jam
yeah
i'm i'm real bishop being coached or
life coached and
and stuff and i think steve from the
other day was like
trying to mentor me and i'm like you're
trying to mentor me you know i mean so
and all i think when i think of life
coaches jpc is now
if you can do the comedy version i'd do
that yes but i liked jp series i like
him less and less as he gets more and
more famous and more and more ecoic
i'm like which happens like that's also
it's like the more influencer you become
that it becomes your like
fake persona and then you have to
whether it's fake or not you have to
play into it it's very much
how influencer culture works i don't
think you can be an influencer without
having that because if you would make
one video
but your audience you know is gonna make
another you was gonna watch the other
video you're gonna make the other video
and so it's going to continually make
these choices again and again and again
that
it leads you down your non-authentic
path
and then you're you know especially when
you have all the influence and all the
people and you have that egoic
thing keep happening and it's like my
version is correct
it's like oh like and he is like i think
he actually was into comedy
like showing like that ironically
i was listening to him talking to
somebody today and he said
from as a kid he loved comedy but as he
became a life coach he felt he had to
suppress that
because people wouldn't think he was
serious and then
you know obviously and then he couldn't
so like stuff it down anymore
and then it came out you know and that's
what he kind of you know i mean
because he did used to make me laugh
because i thought he obviously knows
life coaching
you know i just thought he was a spoof
anyway so have you started your six
weeks then
is that what you've started i don't know
we were just doing a trial because i
have the six week
so i'm still planning on doing this six
weeks part of it is i don't know whether
to just do a six weeks and be the
like kind of be the host and then just
learn from it myself
or whether i want people who want to
build the metamodern learning magic
to this is our first project our product
so come and play with the product and
make it better
right like whether i kind of want to do
it tangent
where like we don't have ownership of it
together it's just me and then i'm
working with random six people to say
yeah how was that
like i'm the owner and they're the
client right and like hey how was that
for you how could i improve it for you
versus this is
ours how do we improve it together
because i want the second one but it's
harder because everyone wants to touch
it and change it and be like well i
think we should have a coach
it's the opposite of what we are doing
right like it's like anyway
so i'm kind of waiting for one of those
things to be concrete and be like yes
this is what you want to do and
following the path
along the way and i think i'm probably
just going to put up an ad on my
facebook
page and see who if with a time pick to
be like who wants to come
who wants to do it would you be
interested in being part of the six week
course gary
i i actually would um so whenever
you're starting it i'd definitely be
interested because i do
i guess as i said uh because of all the
stuff that's going on
i need to focus on getting this this bit
face sorted out because i know whatever
to do
will feed in to what you're doing and be
able to help you and hopefully be able
to assist you a lot more
but i need to i need to get this this
bit
fixed and stable i want that stable
then i'll be able to see who's there
who's got skills to do in what
because i know you like the just the
videos and stuff like that and i know
you need somebody to follow
follow behind you with a dustpan and
shovel
and that's why i guess what i'm saying
is i don't think i do
like part of me is like right someone's
gonna come along and edit my videos i
don't think that's the path this is
gonna take like i don't i think it's
gonna be very distributed i'm never
gonna have a million people watching my
youtube channel that's fine
if i did you could save the world but
that's not like this is about this isn't
about one person becoming the new guru
it's about
everyone becoming their own guru right
and that's never really been done before
it's hard as an underestimator to
convince everyone else who's an
underestimator that we're actually the
ones who are going to save the world
when the underestimators are looking at
the overestimators and being like i
can't possibly do that
you're like you're not supposed to
you're real they're fake like
or whatever some of them are hi what i
just said well i want to get more stable
and as i said i need to do a lot of
practicing on things
to see how they work and stuff and i
think once i've done that i'll be i'll
be more
be able to um because i practice it and
i've done it
and i see now it's worked and tested it
and then that
that way i'll actually be more that more
help to you
i do have an issue with like i create
something in my head and then i never
really test it out am i gonna work
like this like oh yeah that's part of we
need to actually test it and see
right are we progressing how are we at
week one versus how are we at week six
how was it right which is why there's an
entire week devoted to that of like how
was this what would have made it better
what where what did you learn with your
health relationships time and resources
right like what
what was anyway so i think that would do
it in a very new way
it'll be i'm not gonna write all the
stuff well as i said i'd definitely be
interested in taking part now because i
think it would actually help me
um at the stage i'm actually just now to
actually because i know where
i realize that my learning style is very
much through conversation
and talking to people like as i said if
things are bouncing in weird they just
kind of
a little like the the pinball it's like
zoom zoom zoom zoom zoom zoom
but once i've spoken to somebody i'll go
and have a thing could have asleep or
something and then it's like
oh you know three o'clock in the morning
that's what i should be doing
you know i mean and i get sparks
because since my last video kind of been
getting sparks of
a hell of a lot of conversations i've
been having and they've all been sparked
in the right sort of way you know i mean
it's like synchronicities have been
kicking off all over the place and doors
have been opening
which i never even thought and show that
more than it because like
as much as the influencer culture also
does that right like
the right video will show up at the
right time and i'm like how did that
happen that's so weird
but when you're sitting around a table
or a virtual table and the right person
has the right information
or like it's the right information for
you
and it shows up time and time again that
yes that is how we learn that is how we
progress
and it's helpful for everyone like if
you help somebody else that's how like
it's
it's already omni-win for the right
people right if you and this is
where if you feel like you're the expert
and you're just gonna be doling
everything out to everybody else then
you're not
it's not reciprocity right yeah wait i'm
i'm going to be the doctor telling
everyone how to correct their health
instead of like no
no no don't do that that's not what we
need you can be a doctor
and you can have a vision on your health
and people are going to probably be more
likely to listen to you if you give them
your opinion on their health but they
don't have to you're not they're not
your
patients like this yeah that's not what
this is well
well i've been um i've been listening to
there's a podcast called
the disruptive entrepreneur right now i
hate the word entrepreneur
i think you should only say if you're
actually french right
because it sounds it's french weird so
just like so everybody oh you're a
monthly
you're an you're this pretty off
you know what i mean but the guy who
runs it right
is this dodgy geez like well he's not
dodgy but you know i mean
um and he's been having interviews with
um
loads of different people and because
he's fine he was fascinated by
billionaires
millionaires and what got them there
than that and basically i've
been listening to all of the all the
interviews of all the people you've had
so far and i think i've got about 40
left to go
and um and it's basically surround
yourself
with people who are on honest honesty
and transparency
right you know what i mean like as i
know it most in business you know you
know you'll end up being oh you have to
do this you have to do that
but that's not quite right but that's
the way they play it so i've been
listening to all of them
and i've basically found quite a few
people who i'm gonna message later on or
find that you know once or more further
down the line
i'm like right okay then um so i'll find
a way in
to have a chat with them and all of them
of all all these billionaires and then
they're like it's not the money it's the
sense of purpose and fulfillment and
that and
what i like about his podcast is he
asking questions that
nobody else asks and it's really honest
and
it's unedited and i absolutely love that
because you don't often find unedited
stuff
you know what i mean in conversation
it's all kind of because you can see
people's eyes going because there's been
jump cuts you know what i mean
and stuff like that as well you know so
honesty and transparency
all the way all the way that's that's
basically it you know what i mean
so yeah so i'd like him i'd like that
but yeah
conversations are much better for me
learning style
um because as i said it unlocks a load
of things in my mind and with my mum
and my family helping me out with money
till the end of
december 21. it's actually freed my mind
so much that
all the stuff about worrying about going
to pay me mortgage
and i was that's gonna you know what i
mean now i'm gonna eat and am i gonna
have to go scrounging for food off
people
that's all gone for the year so it's
it's it opens my mind
to all sorts of possibilities and
because i need to practice the sales and
marketing
and stuff um because i'm not coming at
it from a point of desperation like
buy my please buy my you know
i really just like you know and i spoke
to somebody
who is in business who is successful in
that and i told him i said oh i'm gonna
have to learn sales and marketing
and that he's like why i said well
well i can't do that he said you you
already kind of
networking and stuff you're really good
at that i said yeah but it's asking
people for money in it
it's it's the selling bit that i can't
kind of
get myself like as if i'm going to
somebody for a chat
i'm hoping that the seeing me is just
coming for the chat but if they start
seeing me or what she's gonna
try and sell me now
you know what i mean yeah which is also
i mean the over underestimation
especially in the life coaching industry
the people the one person i've worked
with as a coach
who was the one person i was like okay
actually i need to pay you because i
need this skill in my life
and they helped me get in touch with my
emotions and
he's no longer a life coach because he
couldn't make a living at it
and it's the very people who don't
really want to charge money
or the best at it and then the ones who
suck at it are
not stuck at it but are like evil
underneath
are the ones who make tons and tons of
money and
it's like it happens time and time again
in business it
like just on repeat that the more
because i can imagine that you one want
to crochet for people you know
right you're like crochet for people i
don't know and you're not going to want
to charge people you know
and so and quite frankly even if you did
even if you had a really awesome etsy
shop right
that you had this following of thousands
and thousands of people they were buying
it off of you
you can't even really make minimum wage
making craps there has to be other ways
of doing it right
the youtube videos the things that are
like on the side
because you're not even making minimum
wage putting in your time and materials
to be able to sell it for that
right and or it's eighty dollars for for
something
and it's like well it's not someone can
go buy the equivalent for five dollars
in the store
we just don't have that pricing built in
um to right like your
effort and passion don't equate to the
dollar amount
and so so dealing with that i think
something like
the mlm i'm creating where people are
able to earn up to 120
000 or 60 000 with the other positions
is like how you actually get paid and
then you can put your passion out in the
world right that those are very
different
versus like to because if you have to
get paid for your passion
then you have to become an influencer it
means you have to market you have to
which means you're not going to be your
authentic self
it's not right you're not going to be
making things for people you know and
love
it's going to have to be for the masses
and this is part of the problem is like
you have to kind of sell your soul to be
successful
and then you've sold your soul happiness
really
i've been really struggling over the
past couple of weeks because i'm
thinking
you know because when i first started
crocheting and stuff i thought well i'm
just going to make stuff for people who
i love respect and appreciate
and then i can just make them and send
it off there you go and they didn't even
know they were getting anything
you know i mean they're just like what's
your favorite colors you know like how
sad people ask what's your favorite
colors you know i mean and
and i love that just to being able to
just give somebody
and now i'm gonna have to kind of force
to kind of
put a price on things and i'm like well
i've got to find a kind of middle way
where i can
make stuff and just send it to someone
because i love them respect them and
appreciate them
yeah but so i was thinking i'll make the
other stuff really expensive and
exclusive
and then that way if someone buys it
because my fear was what if somebody
really horrible
gets the lands on this i don't want to
go into horrible people
wandering around where they would have
made them if they're being attracted to
other people
i don't want that you know i mean and
there's no way of gauging that if you're
having to sell to
the the wider world you know i mean and
and when i was thinking about the market
i do um
i thought well it's more i want you know
like etsy in that everybody goes to
their site because they want to sell
something
right i think i think i want um people
to come
to a site because of the community and
the people there and whatever
they're up to then that can sweep into
the
the market but the people are there for
the other people
not for what you know i mean and it
i don't know whether i probably shade a
business i couldn't this
this probably might be like mother
doing the six week course right the six
week course that i'm designing that is
about us coming together and figuring it
it is very much from that model and this
is part of my issue is the game be i
want to retire the game b people the
game b
people are already up to amazing things
those are the people i want to retire
but the game b people don't necessarily
see the value in a six-week course of
that peer-to-peer
if they would if it was just game b
people but they're like oh not what the
unwashed mass is
like it's like they have to be at the
that's not what they're saying those are
my language but like that same level of
are you here to help everyone right do
you want to help other people yes then
let's have a conversation and let's help
each other
because guess what even if we help each
other a little bit with our goals in
life
we're unlocking the the potential of
good human beings
and then they have more potential and
they're inviting them more people that
that is literally just
the metric of do you want help and do
you want to help other people
if it's yes to both of those options and
honestly even if it's you don't want
help
you want to help helping other people is
the bigger part but people get to one
through the other
people come to help themselves and end
up helping other people and realizing
how awesome that is or they come to help
other people and realize oh i got help
too
that it's it's about are we here to help
one another and then how do we grow out
from there
and part of it is me seeing off
time and time again that the people who
are good aren't the people making money
and the people making money are often
the evilest worst people on the planet
and it's like no we and you can't just
switch that right you can't just be a
good person to make it in business
because you're never you can you can be
a good person to make it in business but
you're never going to make it the same
as someone who's evil and lying
and so you're never going to be as
successful as that person
which means they always have an
advantage it's the entire system that's
broken
but i do think we can create something
beautiful from within that then grows
out in the most
you know sounds like cancer but it's
more like a crystal crystal formation
and crystal growing out and you can't
really tell who started it you can't
really tell
um it's just beautiful and growing yeah
let's go with crystal
instead of the other horrific branding
cancer organ crystal
which one and kerry you might want to
look into um
what's called solution sales because
i've done sales in the past and
i'm horrible at it but um
what people think of as like normal
sales is really
selling stuff that maybe either
shouldn't be sold or they don't believe
in or isn't the
the best like it's the ability to you
know sell ice to an eskimo
is the term that people use for like a
good sales person
we're like yeah that term is selling
somebody something they don't need
which i don't know why that's the the
benchmark
part of the sales i did was selling
computers and i know computers and i
wasn't a good salesperson as far as
the company i was working for was
concerned but yet like i still helped
people and i sold things and people came
back to me and
i was able to sell things because i
didn't care about the profit margin or
this i cared about helping that person
and that part and that anybody can do
because you're just talking to a
another person and say okay tell me what
you need okay no no that
that that computer's massive overkill
for what you want go look over here
which isn't something a normal sales
person would do but something that's not
a salesperson and just someone who
who who's helping which is also like
if you had something that you knew could
sell for a hundred dollars but you had a
price at twenty dollars
i bet you you you could sell that no
problem because you're like well wait
it's selling over here for per 100 it's
only 20 here
that's something that you can sell your
friends and family on and it's that same
conversation
it's the what's it worth and what we
think of the sales at
marketing is sort of you know snake oil
selling ice eskimos and sorry for
continuing using that word i know that
it's not great but still
that's right the end goal is what we're
seeing
are the people that like kind of the the
overestimators right those are the
people that go to
the top because they can sell anything
and that's their skill set
but like that's not a skill set that you
necessarily need to cultivate
right yeah because i was also having a
look at sponsorship as well
sponsorship and i was there's a guy
there who runs a sponsorship
collective i think his name is just
bayless he's canadian
i think he's in vancouver or no ottawa i
think no
he's in canada somewhere right so anyway
he put out all these videos on
sponsorships
and stuff and and it was like you know
getting to know
them who you're speaking to and who
their audience is
and and they and he said you know if
you're going in with a sponsorship deal
asking them for money straight away
that's a big though you just don't do
that
so i've learned a lot from from that so
i would say
that's like like getting sponsors as an
influencer or what do you mean
so sponsorship right um because i
pop before my mum give me the money
right
i thought okay how much do i need to
stay alive for the next
kind of year to nobody's gonna give me a
job i can't get a job
you know i mean i'm gonna have to do
something and i thought right okay so if
i thought well if i find
50 people who'd be willing to give me 20
quid a month for a year
and then that would help me get on my
feet and then i thought well that's
going to take me ages
get into that but i wanted to build it
like a sponsorship package so
they weren't just giving me it for
nothing
but but they would be there for me to
practice on
practice sales and marketing because i
said look you know i've got to do this
and i've got to do that and
i've got a clue about that but i'm going
to have to try this traditional and
and build a bull part of the reason and
i was watching another video
um about money and stuff and that and he
was like
find the problems what people chase the
problems not the money
right so in order like i'm me thinking
in this
this that i ask people for 20 quid for
the year
for the month you know i mean to give me
then that would give me a
chance to actually get to know them and
finding out what problems
that they had and then as part of the
sponsorship package
like some of them may be working some of
them maybe not part of the sponsorship
package would be like building stuff
that's actually giving them stuff that's
useful to them
that so they didn't feel like they were
just giving it and getting nothing back
and then it was all about finding
whoever
you're going to and you know and he said
instead of going to all the sort of like
the giving organizations you know the
philanthropy and all of that
go to the business development
communications
brand management and there was something
else
go and ask go go to them
for the sponsorship and find out who
their audiences are
we you know where they are what problems
they're having you know what i mean but
you've got to build up the audience
yourself and see who's within your
audience so it's all about audience and
i kind of ate the word audience because
like you know not on the stage you know
just not performing and that but i hate
the way so like if you if you've built a
community you could practice on the
community
and find out you know i said it would
take time but it's actually
having a conversation that would find
out who their audience is and aligning
what the people who you're interested in
are they're interested in and then
coming up with experiences
just all these buzzwords experiences
for the sponsor and that you know your
audiences will love anyway
but because the your your your audience
is
a sponsorships audience um they would
would be able to sponsor it and they
would love it and blah blah blah
so i was like well that's interesting
because as i said i never thought about
that
but that i mean as i said i've been
learning a lot it's all kinds of
swirling around me i'd like big
you know you know the sales market as i
said there's still lots i've got lots to
learn but um
yeah so sales marketing sponsorship
and and this sponsorship collective he
said he wants to do it
carrie we're we're at the hour and i
know you're gonna i'm waiting for you to
stop but it's not good
there's something in the six week course
that is um
without the sponsorship exactly what
you're looking to do so i say we do it
and there might be something in that
that offers you
what you're what it was coming through
barbara shearer for you that you can
bring
to a knitting circle or something right
because it's kind of almost what
naturally happens in a knitting circle
or a it's like you're talking about your
problems and helping each other this is
just a more structured version of that
but giving somebody those tools and
maybe you can take a version of it and
go off and play with it so
they are at the hour though so i just
want to say goodbye to youtube and
facebook
and we will see you next week on friday